Darryn Anton Jordan

Newlands, Cape Town - South Africa

☐ +27 73 470 2710 • ☐ darrynjordan@icloud.com darrynjordan.github.io

Ph.D. candidate at the University of Cape Town (UCT), South Africa. Specialised in frequency-modulated continuous-wave (FMCW) synthetic aperture radar (SAR). Passionate about digital signal processing and system design, with strong technical and interpersonal skills.

Formal Education

University of Cape Town

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering in Radar, Submitted for examination.

University of Cape Town

B.Sc. in Electrical Engineering in Mechatronics, Graduated with honours.

Hudson Park High School

National Senior Certificate, Graduated with honours.

Cape Town, South Africa 2016-2020

Cape Town, South Africa

2012-2015

East London, South Africa 2007-2011

Relevant Experience

Development of the miloSAR

Cape Town, South Africa

2016-Present

University of Cape Town Design and implementation of a low-cost FMCW SAR, known as the miloSAR. This project provided experience in radar signal processing, which included the FPGA-based implementation of DSP algorithms such as digital down-conversion, FIR filtering and coherent integration. Furthermore, a novel spur suppression algorithm was developed as part of the project. This algorithm was validated with simulated and measured data. Well-developed planning and organisational skills were required for a project of this scope in addition to high technical ability in terms of software, gateware and hardware.

Development of the NeXtRAD Quick-Look Processor

Cape Town, South Africa

University of Cape Town

2015-2017

Development of NeXtLook: A multi-threaded quick-look processor for the UCT NeXtRAD radar. NeXtLook implements pulse compression and Doppler processing algorithms to produce range-time-intensity and range-Doppler plots for real-time data validation. This work resulted in exposure to the FFTW, OpenCV and Boost libraries. While its final C++ implementation leverages CPU multi-threading, a GPU-based implementation in CUDA was also investigated.

Technical Skills

- **Software:** Python, C/C++, Matlab, CUDA.
- o Gateware: Verilog (Vivado & Quartus).
- o Hardware: Xilinx Zyng 7010 (Red Pitaya), LMX2492EVM, Emlid Reach M+ RTK GNSS, Jetson TK1, STM32F0, Altera MAX 10 (DE10-Lite), Arduino, Raspberry Pi.
- o Equipment: Spectrum Analysers, Network Analysers, Oscilloscopes, Multi-meters.
- o Operating Systems: Linux, Windows.
- Other: Git, LATEX.

Positions of Responsibility

2020: Undergraduate Project Supervisor.

2020: IET Radar, Sonar & Navigation Journal Peer Reviewer.

2020: Space Studies Masters Programme Remote Exam Administrator.

2019–2020: Radar Masters Programme Teacher's Assistant.

2017–2018: Signals & Systems II Tutored Reassessment Programme (TRP) Assistant Lecturer.

2017: Embedded Systems I Tutor.

2016: Signals & Systems II Teacher's Assistant.

Recent Journal Publications

IEEE Transactions on Microwave Theory and Techniques

"Suppression of Spur Chirps for Fractional-N PLL-Based Heterodyne FMCW SAR" D. A. Jordan, M. R. Inggs, M. Y. Abdul Gaffar, 2020, DOI: 10.1109/TMTT.2020.3030273

• IET Electronics Letters
• "Integer Boundary Spur Considerations for Fractional-N PLL Based FMCW Radar" D. A. Jordan, M. R. Inggs, M. Y. Abdul Gaffar, 2020, DOI: 10.1049/EL.2020.0764

References

Dr. Michael Inggs: Emeritus Professor, University of Cape Town (mikings@gmail.com)

Dr. Yunus Gaffar: Senior Lecturer, University of Cape Town (yunus.abdulgaffar@uct.ac.za)

Dr. Stephen Paine: Lecturer, University of Cape Town (stephen.paine@uct.ac.za)